<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Visual Computing</title><link>https://vc-project.github.io/vc/docs/shortcodes/shaders/</link><description>Recent content on Visual Computing</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vc-project.github.io/vc/docs/shortcodes/shaders/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://vc-project.github.io/vc/docs/shortcodes/shaders/shaders/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vc-project.github.io/vc/docs/shortcodes/shaders/shaders/</guid><description>Shaders # ‿︵‿︵‿︵‿︵‿︵‿︵‿︵‿︵‿︵‿︵‿︵‿︵‿︵‿︵‿︵‿︵‿︵‿︵‿︵‿︵‿︵‿︵‿︵
Image Processing # Image processing means processing digital images by means of digital computers. There are two important goals in this field: to extract useful information and to enhance or improve value and quality of images. Image digital processing strongly implies using different computational alghoritms based on both mathematical and cognitive research. An image is defined as a two-dimensional function, F(x,y), where x and y are spatial coordinates, and amplitude values of F are finite.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://vc-project.github.io/vc/docs/shortcodes/shaders/VideoByHardware/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vc-project.github.io/vc/docs/shortcodes/shaders/VideoByHardware/</guid><description>Hardware # Here we show a video processed frame by frame using the hardware approach of image processing. GPU capabilities are used to improve performance. This video consists of an mp4 file which is used to draw a photomosaic version of the video.
Checkboxes are displayed to activate basic pixelator shader or Photomosaic versions of the video. A slider allows to change sample patch size.
"</description></item><item><title/><link>https://vc-project.github.io/vc/docs/shortcodes/shaders/VideoBySoftware/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vc-project.github.io/vc/docs/shortcodes/shaders/VideoBySoftware/</guid><description>Software # Here we show a video processed frame by frame using the Software approach of image processing. This video consists of an mp4 file which is used to draw a photomosaic version of the video.
A Checkbox is displayed to show or hide the Photomosaic version of the video and a slider allows to change the sample patch size.
"</description></item></channel></rss>