<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Visual Computing</title><link>https://vc-project.github.io/vc/docs/shortcodes/illusions/</link><description>Recent content on Visual Computing</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vc-project.github.io/vc/docs/shortcodes/illusions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://vc-project.github.io/vc/docs/shortcodes/illusions/Concentric-Rectangle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vc-project.github.io/vc/docs/shortcodes/illusions/Concentric-Rectangle/</guid><description>Concentric rectangle # The illusion consist of a concentric rectangle whic rotates in the center of the canvas consecutively. A concentric rectangle share the center with the canvas, and, with a rotation rate, rotate until it has an effect of an spiral in the canvas.
Applications # A possible appplication of this effect can be, in addition to sam the visual system, in research about the behaviour of the human visualization in specific conditions and image processing.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://vc-project.github.io/vc/docs/shortcodes/illusions/HermannGrid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vc-project.github.io/vc/docs/shortcodes/illusions/HermannGrid/</guid><description>Hermann Grid # The Hermann grid illusion is an optical illusion reported by Ludimar Hermann in 1870. The illusion is characterized by &amp;ldquo;ghostlike&amp;rdquo; grey blobs perceived at the intersections of a white (or light-colored) grid on a black background. The grey blobs disappear when looking directly at an intersection.
Illusion # Ludimar Hermann, a German physiologist, discovered this illusion reading a physics text in which the figures were printed in a matrix-like arrengement.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://vc-project.github.io/vc/docs/shortcodes/illusions/Pinna-Illusion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vc-project.github.io/vc/docs/shortcodes/illusions/Pinna-Illusion/</guid><description>Pinna illusions # Pinna illusions encomposses various optical ilusions discovered by Dr. Baingio Pinna. We are gonna focus here on just two of them, composed by identical squares positioned in circular orbits around the center of the image. The position and shading of the squares creates the perception of spiraling orbits in the first one and in the second one the illusion of movement.
Pinna&amp;rsquo;s intertwining illusion # One can see an array of squares in a seemingly spiraling position.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://vc-project.github.io/vc/docs/shortcodes/illusions/Zollner/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vc-project.github.io/vc/docs/shortcodes/illusions/Zollner/</guid><description>Zöllner Illusion # This illusion belongs to a family of illusions called geometrical-optical illusions. In these illusions some objects appear distorted in virtue of other aspects of the image and their geometrical properties as length, straightness, or parallelism are not correctly perceived.
The illusion consists of a series of parallel, diagonal lines which are crossed by short lines. The direction of the crossing lines alternate between horizontal and vertical. The created optical effect gets the observer to think that the diagonal lines are not parallel, but indeed they are.</description></item></channel></rss>